Benedict Thompson

• 07964-629-416

•me@benjft.uk

• github.com/benjft

• linkedin.com/in/benjft

I'm an experienced software developer with a preference for backend technologies. Currently I work in a back end focused role, though still occasionally dabble in front end components. My professional experience is centred on C# and .Net, and use of Microsoft SQL Server. I have experience using Azure to host applications, both Azure Function and App Services. I also have experience creating, adapting, and improving CI/CD pipelines to streamline development and deployment processes.

Experience

Back End Software Developer, September 2024 - Present

Mercury Xrm, Coleshill, Hybrid

- Back end position working on integrations with 3rd parties.
- Projects focused based solutions using Azure Functions and App services.
- Helped plan and implement an integration with LinkedIn, ensuring the integration met official certification criteria.
- Improved team development experience by overhauling the dependency injection boilerplate used in many projects, reducing developer errors and bugs while reducing the amount of boilerplate code needed.
- Created plugins to interact with Microsoft Power Apps and Microsoft Dynamics.
- Responsible for providing peer review on PRs, helping catch bugs and missed functionality early.

Software Developer, June 2023 – August 2024

Gold-Vision CRM, Northampton, Hybrid

- Full stack developer, specialising in MSSQL Server, .Net, and React.
- Contributed to development of the core CRM product.
- Design and implemented features, such as a middleware layer to automatically track and report feature usage and uptake to help inform business decisions.
- Scoped, quoted, and built bespoke integrations according to customer needs.
- Modified an existing OData API to make it more flexible, allowing custom models/endpoints to be defined in SQL allowing customers to achieve better reporting.
- Responsible for mentoring our junior team member by overseeing their personal development time, helping them plan stories, and suggesting resources they could look at to improve.
- Manage the team Kanban in Jira, ensuring all tasks being worked on are up to date, and organising estimating and refinement of new tasks from the backlog.
- Improved existing CI pipelines, reducing build and test times by over 50% with no loss of functionality.
- Delivered presentations to customers demonstrating custom features they had requested.
- Investigated, proposed, and implemented solutions for issues arising from Azure migration, including container customization and third-party services.

Junior Software Developer, August 2022 - June 2023

Gold-Vision CRM, Northampton, Hybrid

Education

Computer Science, BSc (Hons), Coventry University, 1st

Physics with Theoretical Physics, Undergraduate Diploma, University of Nottingham

Additional Learning

- MSSQL Mastering Performance Tuning Brent Ozar Online Courses
- MSSQL One Day Fundamentals, Brent Ozar Online Courses